Guide to the Sidney W. Mandel Collection of English Legal Documents ca. 1519 - ca. 1920
University of Chicago Library
Mandel, Sidney W.. Collection of English Legal Documents
ca. 1519 - ca. 1920
5.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Sidney W. Mandel Collection of English Legal Documents contains miscellaneous English legal documents collected by the Chicago attorney during his travels in England. Interested in the similarities between modern day American legal terminology and that of the English courts, Mandel assembled a variety of documents including mortgages, leases, wills, and marriage settlements. The collection spans the sixteenth through twentieth centuries, but the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries are best represented, with a majority of the documents originating in London and in the counties surrounding and to the south of the capital. Most of the manuscripts are inscribed on parchment, with many bearing well-preserved seals.
Information on Use
Access
No restrictions.
Scope Note
The Sidney W. Mandel English Legal Documents Collection contains miscellaneous English legal documents collected by the Chicago attorney during his travels in England. Interested in the similarities between modern day American legal terminology and that of the English courts, Mandel assembled a variety of documents including mortgages, leases, wills, and marriage settlements. The collection spans the sixteenth through twentieth centuries, but the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries are best represented, with a majority of the documents originating in London and in the counties surrounding and to the south of the capital. Most of the manuscripts are inscribed on parchment, with many bearing well-preserved seals.
The documents in the collection are arranged chronologically, oversized documents have been placed at the end of the collection.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Manuscripts, English; Legal documents-Great Britain
INVENTORY
- Agreement to purchase house, Sarah Stevens of Eton Thomas Vaughan of Eton (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Lease, 2 February 10 Henry VIII (1519) Richard, Abbot of Sts. Peter and Paul Roger Nialles of Betton, et al. Pasture called the Home at Emstre (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Rent roll, 17th c. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Account fragment, 17th c. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Rent receipts, unidentified, 17th c. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Estate inventory, unidentified,17th c. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Survey of land at Naissey, 17th c. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Land survey of Mr. Lomans, Naissey, 17th c. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Conveyance, September I James, 1603 Thomas Horde of Bridgewolf Robert Darkombe of Bymhall Land in Horde Parish (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Settlement, 24 February 3 James, 1606 William Jones of Shrewsbury Thomas Powell of Markshall (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Deed, 13 James I (1616) Robert Daxombe Launcelot Ridley Bynhall farm (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Grant, 25 October 3 Charles (1627) Richard Ridley of Bridgwood Sir William Whitmore of Ashley (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lease, 5 August 1649 Sir Humphrey Forster of Aldermaston Sir John Evelyn of West Deane House, lands at Aldermaston (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lease, 25 March 1656 John Huxley Michael Stephens Meadow land in Nordley woods (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bond, 26 February 1668 Thomas and Mary Hollis of London Suzanna Andrewes of London Land on Thames Street, London (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Rent roll of Mr. Lomans, 1669 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lease, 10 November 1673 Thomas Bradley of Old Swinford John Caddif of Stonebridge (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Marriage settlement, 26 September 25 Charles II (1674) Francis Huxley of Stanley Elizabeth, Daughter of Sir Thomas Jones (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Annuity for life, 10 November 25 Charles II (1675) Bartholomew Hall of Harding Court James White of Harding Court (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Accounts from Naissey, 1682. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Rents for estate of Richard Holford, 1684 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Lease, 10 May 1692 Sir Humphrey Forster of Aldermaston Benjamin Griffin of Whitchurch (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Chirograph, 1694 Lancelot Taylor Huxley Pentland (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Articles of agreement, 21 September 6 William and Mary (1694) John Huxley the Elder of Stanley John Huxley the Younger Thomas Whitford of Bridgeworth (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Bond of Joseph Jones of Chilton as High Sheriff, 28 December 1699 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Indenture, 28 December 11 William III (1699) Thomas Jones, High Sheriff, County Salop Joseph Jones of Chilton Duties to be performed as undersheriff (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Land accounts, unidentified, 18th c. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Proposal for common use of land within Astley Manor, 18th c. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Lease, June 1700, John Huxley Lancelot Stephens Richard Phillips House at Ashley, Salop (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Unidentified expense account, 1701. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Estimate of rent receipts, 1702. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Rent due and received, Lady Day 1708. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Estate accounts, unidentified, 1709 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Accounts, unidentified, 1711 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bond, 26 February 1712 Christopher Wells John Adams (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lease, 22 February 2 George (1715) William Mills of Compton William Underwood of Loutmore (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Mortgage, 20 November 3 George (1716) Jeremy Taylor of Naseby Richard Reynolds of Naseby (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Lease, 7 May 4 George (1718) Abraham Bonifield of Reading Thomas Ledbetter of Aldermaston (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Bond of indemnity, 4 September 1720 Thomas Ledbetter of Aldermaston Luke Standsmore of Farnham Royal (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Lease, 14 September 1720 Thomas Ledbetter of Aldermaston Luke Standsmore of Farnham Royal Land at Aldermaston (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Bond, 14 September 1720 Thomas Ledbetter of Aldermaston Luke Standsmore of Farnham Royal (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Mortgage, 22 January 8 George (1721) Jeremy Taylor of Naseby William Hashwood of Apley (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Lease, 24 June 1721 Edward Jones of New Windsor William Henry Robsin of London House in Wathing Street, London (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Assignment of mortgage, 19 November 2 George II (1728) James Hashwood of Bridgeworth Benjamin Phillips of Eardington (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Lease, 29 September 1732 Thomas Ridge of Portsmouth John Robins of Burley Lands called Wards Acre on Burley Manor (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Lease, 15 November 1732 Thomas Ridge of Portsmouth James Robins of Burley Collets Corner on Burley Manor (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Lease, 5 September 1733 Thomas Ridge of Portsmouth David Bromfield of Burley Lands on Burley Manor (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Last will and testament, J. Thomas Waugh, 2 December 1734 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Abstract of title, 5 May 1737 Benjamin Taylor James Hashwood Estate at Deepdale (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Grant of land, 20 March 12 George II (1738) Charles and Frances Daniel of Earsham Mary Carter of Cavendish (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Lease, 19 April 1739 Thomas Ridge of Burley William Young of Burley Land on Burley Manor (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Assignment of mortgage, 16 June 18 George II (1744) Rev. John Prosper of Langenmouth, et al. Thomas Fletcher of Monmouth Property on Bark Land and Grinder Street, Monmouth (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Bond for performance of covenant, 16 June 18 George II (1744) Mary William Monmouth Thomas Fletcher of Monmouth (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Lease, 16 March 19 George II (1745) Sir Thomas Whitmore of Ashley Rowland Smothyman of Rimdleford House and crops on Ashley Manor (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Lease, 18 September 21 George II (1747) Edward Jones of Stanley John Ardley of Bresley 21 year lease on smith shop (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Lease, 2 August 1748 Edward Jones of Stanley Richard Goary of Stanley Rental of Stanley House (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Lease, 30 September 1751 Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley John Seamell Land near Pool Pond, Burley Manor (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Lease, 11 November 25 George II (1751) Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley Anne Browning of Burley Land at Bistern Close, Burley Manor (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Lease, 11 November 25 George II (1751) Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley Anne Browning of Burley 3 acres at Chalky Close, Burley Manor (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Articles of agreement, 18 December 1751 Richard Jones of Bridgeworth Edward Jones of Stanley Promise to furnish water through pipe system (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Release of mortgage, 1 September 1752 John Swarbeck of Oporto, Portugal Bartholomew Prust of London Lands near Loughton, Essex (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Probate of will of Henry Gee of Oporto, Portugal, 21 January 1754 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Deed of use, 12 July 1756 Bartholomew Prust of London Benjamin Ashwood of Charterhouse Square Land near Loughton in Essex (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Lease, 25 March 30 George II (1757) Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley Flower and William Etheridge of Burley Pastures at Heathy Close at Burley Manor (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Lease, 7 December 1758 Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley William Browning of Burley Tenement known as New Inn, Burley Manor (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Baptismal certificate, Henry Alcock of Englefield 13 March 1760 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Lease, 25 July 1760 Ralph Congreve of Aldermaston George Dearon of Streatly (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Lease, 14 August 4 George III (1760) Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley John Harris of Fordingbridge Timber and hunting rights on Burley Manor (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Lease, 14 August 1760 Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley John Harris of Fordingbridge Right to enclose Commons of Berten Close (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Lease, 25 June 3 George III (1763) Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley John Young of Burley Lands of Burley Battin (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Lease, 25 June 1763 Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley Thomas Coles of Burley House and gardens at Bistern Close, Burley (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Lease, 25 June 1763 Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley William Rooke of Rhinefield Lodge Land at Bistern Close, Burley Manor (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Purchase release, 20 August 3 George III (1763) Elizabeth Williams of Glasburg James Parry of Hay (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Probate of will and testament, 1771, Thomas Middleton of Monmouth (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Last will of William Lake of Kingwood, 6 September 1771 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Probate of will, John Adams of Aldermaston 3 July 1773 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Reconveyance, 24 December 1776 Robert Baker of Streatley Sir Henry Bridgeman of Weston (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Lease, 25 November 19 George III (1778) Legatees of John Scammell of Burley John Johns of Blackford Smith's house and barn at Burley Manor (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Lease, 25 March 26 George III (1786) James Mowbray of Burley Joseph Emberly of Kingwood Bistern Close, Burley Manor (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Extract of will of Dorcas Adams of Aldermaston, 5 October 1786 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Last will and testament, Mary Englefield of Aldermaston 30 December 1789 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Receipt of legacy, 4 March 1791 Martha Wicks of Aldermaston (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Receipt of legacy, 4 March 1791 Mrs. Mary May of Aldermaston (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Receipt of legacy, 4 March 1791 Martha Wicks of Aldermaston (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Receipt of legacy, 12 March 1791 Sarah Self of Newbury (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Lease, 29 September 1792 Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley William Brown of Burley Land at Burley Lane and Moore Common (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Last will, Joan Sims of Aldermaston, 13 April 1794 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Probate of Will, William Yarley of Biggelswade 27 May 1794 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Mortgage, 14 July 1797 Thomas Englefield of Aldermaston Francis Webb of Aldermaston Security for loan of £200 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Release of moeity, 26 November 1800 Elizabeth Brown of Newbury John Thompson of AIdermaston Land at Aldermaston (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Assignment of 500 year trust, 26 December 1800 Francis Webb and Thomas Englefield of Aldermaston William Stephens of Aldermaston (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Assignment of bond, 25 March 1806 Joseph Smith of Bridgeworth Richard Phillips of Wyke (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Lease, 4 August 48 George III (1808) Robert Rolfe of East Church John Budgen and executors of John Rolfe of Plumstead Land at Loggs Hill, Bromley (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Lease, 24 February 1809 George James Gorham of St. Neets John Dowille of Hammersmith Jonathan Moreing of Hammersmith Copyhold at Fulham Manor (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Power of attorney, 11 February 1812 Joseph Marechaux of Holborn William Anderson Portal of London (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Mortgage, 9 April 1812 Thomas Wilmott of Manchester Executors of Marry Wilmott of Manchester House and land in Rusholme, Lancs. (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Mortgage, 4 January 54 George III (1814) William Posthumous Chapeau of Catherinton Thomas Hall of Martin Hussingtree Estates at Martin Hussingtree Hall (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Deed of covenant, 1 May 56 George III (1816) Mr. John Saper of Aldermaston John Ruddle (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Conveyance, 13 May 57 George III (1817) Mary Fisher of Tintern John Rowbotham of Tintern Abbey House and currier shop near Tintern Abbey (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Lease, 9 June 1817 James Hardwick of Monmouth John Poulos of Huntsham House in Grinder Street, Monmouth (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Lease, 24 October 1820 Thomas Woolett of Monmouth Thomas Embry of Monmouth House and land in Monmouth (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Admission to copyhold at Fulham, 19 April 1824 William Pike (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Bond to secure £300, 23 June 1824 Richard Martin Bird, Greenwich William Rice of Fenchurch, London (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Mortgage, 2 October 1824 Ann Bennett of Newtown George Hopkinson of Nottingham Land at Stanton on the Woulds, Nottingham (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Lease, 19 December 1825 Richard Martin Bird of Greenwich John Carter of London Tenement on Fenchurch Street, London (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Assignment of mortgage, 28 October 1826 George Henry Woakes of Worcester William Roe of Dodderhill Land at Martin Hussingtree, Worcs. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Probate of will of Samuel King of Sangford, 19 January 1828 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Assignment of mortgage, 16 April 1829 William Culley of Exmouth John Elcox of Berwardine House and land at Exmouth (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Mortgage, 23 May 1834 David West of Fulstow William Grant Allison of Louth Tenemant in Fulstow (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Admission to freehold, 27 March 1837 William Pike of Hammersmith Lands on Fulham Manor (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Probate of will, Susann Moncrieffe of Sexton 26 May 1837 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Extract from will, William Kittier of Damerham 21 December 1838 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Lease, 14 May 1842 Richard Sparkes of Wonersh, et al. Henry Hales of Walworth Houses at Nos. 9 and 10 Saville Row, Walworth Road, Surrey (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Lease, 18 November 1842 James, George, and Richard Bird of Leamington Henry Miller of London No. 140 Fenchruch Street, London (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Lease, 3 November 1843 Charles Lord Clinton of Springfield Harry James of Exeter Henry Southcott of Exmouth House in Exmouth (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Mortgage, 7 May 1847 Charles Narin Haistie of Lingfield Walter Henry Hitchcock of Berkeley Square Estate of Edward Cranston (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Account of indenture, 1853 Marmaduke Wyvil of Spennthorne, York (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Declaration as to marriage, 19 October 1853 John Ayles of Fordingbridge Sarah Ann Palmer (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Probate of will, Benjamin Coley of Marstown 23 November 1854 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Lease, 23 May 1856 Thomas Powell of Hammersmith George Heathcott of Kensington Land at Fitzroy Rd. and Walden Rd., Middlesex (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Lease, 12 September 1856 Charles Smale of Lawrence Lane, London George Heathcott of Kensington No. 11 St. George's Terrace, London (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Lease, 15 September 1856 Charles Smale of London George Heathcott of Kensington No. 13 St. George's Terrace, London (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Lease, 26 September 1856 Charles Smale of Cheapside, London William Evill of Bushey House, Streatham Nos. 2-13, St. George's Terrace, London (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Lease, 31 December 1858 Trustees of John Lord Rolle William Huxtable of Busby Park House and land known as Busby Park, Exmouth (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Lease, 8 January 1859 John Thirst of Paddington James Frost of Paddington No. 21 Kildare Gardens, Paddington (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Assignment of leasehold, 5 February 1859 William Evill of Bushey Islip Odell of Upper Clapton Nos. 2-13 St. George's Terrace, London (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Lease, 1 February 1860 Islip Odell of Upper Clapton Frederich Boulton Barton of Lambs Conduit No. 2-13 St. George's Terrace, London (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Covenant to surrender, 27 January 1865 Benjamin Franklin Stevens of Covent Garden Charlotte and Charles Whittingham of Richmond Land at Hammersmith on Fulham Manor (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Lease, 15 March 1866 Trustees of John Lord Rolle William Gay of Exmouth Premises of Bicton Street, Exmouth (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Covenant to surrender, 1 September 1866 Peter Nevell of Whitton William and Ann Long of Hounslow Copyhold at Whitton (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Admission to copyhold, 8 November 1867 Elizabeth Eleanor Whittingham Lands at Fulham Manor (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Admission out of court, 28 July 1868 Benjamin and Charlotte Stevens of Kingston Charles John Whittingham of Chancery Lane Land at Hammersmith (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Settlement of lease, 3 August 1868 Charles John Whittingham of Hammersmith James Fell Puttick of Leicester Square Land at Fulham Manor (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Bond certification, 19 Janaury 1871 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Administration of will, Montague Chambers 30 October 1885 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Lease, 19 March 1890 Harold Seymer Whitcher of Kinnington Park No. 3 Borough of Lambeth Permanent Building Society No. 3 Horace Street, Lambeth (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Admission to freehold, 14 August 1900 Charles John Whittingham of London Manor of Fulham (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Assignment by trustees, 3 June 1901 Trustees of Richard Arnold of Binley John Thomas Harmer of Peckham Nos. 90 and 92 St. George's Road, Peckham (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Appointment of Trustees for will of John Charles Fletcher of Dale, Park, Arundel 17 April 1902 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Deed of Conveyance, 10 July 1902 Ashford (Middlesex) Parish Council Frederick George Hodgson Stanwell Road plot (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Conveyance, 1903 William Albert Dawson Alfred Dawson 1/2 share reversion of hereditary lands in Rushmore, Suffolk (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Mortgage of freehold, 13 January 1904 Henry Cresswell Foulkes of Cambridge Lt. Col. Henry Casker of Frimley Green Land at Denton Road and Alexandra Road, Twickenham (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Admission to freehold, 16 June 1904 Charles John Whittingham of Trafalgar Square Lands on Fulham Manor (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Reconveyance, 29 June 1905 Selwood Cooke Riddle of Wolverhampton Frederick George Hodgson of London Nos. 56, 57 Hutton Hall Estate, Shenfield (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Transfer of mortgage, 3 December 1907 Henry J. Wenham of Parkhurst Haselmere Thomas Walter Bacon of Ramsden Hall Nos. 69, 71, 73 Talbot Road, Paddington (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Release of land, 13 December 1907 Edward L. W. Johns of Stowe Hill, et al. John Charles Payan and George Trapps of Queen Victoria Street Several plots, Kent Park Building Estate, Margate (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Enrollment of order, 23 October 1908 William Whittingham of Fulham Legacy of land at Hammersmith Fulham Manor (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Assignment by trustees, 16 August 1909 Trustees of will of Charles John Whittingham Jane Whittingham of Chiswick One fourth copyhold Grove Place, Hammersmith (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Covenant, 16 August 1909 Trustees of Charlotte Stevens of Surbiton Jane Whittingham of Chiswick Cottage, Surbiton 1/4 share copyhold in Fulham Manor (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Trustee assignment, 16 August 1909 Trustees of William Whittingham Jane Whittingham of Surbiton 1/4 share copyhold, Fulham Manor (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Unidentified fragment (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Unidentified fragment (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Unidentified fragment (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Articles of Agreement, 1 October 1625 Walter Aston of Earlswood John Weld of Willowy Heald (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Will and probate of John Pooler, 11 August 1657 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Mortgage, 30 April 12 George (1725) William Hashwood of Ashley William Whitmore of Ashley (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Indenture, 4 George II (1730) Edward Jones of Lincoln's Inn Margery Huxley of Stanby Binhall farm (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Release of indenture, 22 George II (1748) Edward Jones of Stanby Richard Acton of Bridgworth (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Mortgage, 10 June 1760 John Morley of Starthouse Thomas Fisher Estate of Starthouse, Essex (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Lease, 14 May 2 George III (1762) Sir Thomas Ridge of Burley Sir William Lake of Ringwood Land on Burley Manor (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Article of agreement to perform as sheriff, 27 February 11 George III (1771) (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Release and conveyance, 28 September 16 George III (1776) James Blatch of Colchester George Ward of London Joseph Doyle of Stratford Release of estate of William Talbot (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Lease, 23 October 1811 Robert Avery Webb of Holkestone Thomas Castle of Holkestone 2 tenements in Holkestone, Kent (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Commissioner's conveyance, 4 Janaury 54 George III (1814) Commissioners of Newbiggen Enclosure Act William Purchas of Burton William Wray of Hestholme Allotment in Newbiggen pasture (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Indenture of assignment, 19 January 1816 John Howell of Tinthorn Mary Fisher of Tinthorn Lease of unspecified manor (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Mortgage, 15 December 1816 James Underdown Nicholas Crofts Wellington Crescent, Kent (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Assignment of mortgage, 11 March 1817 Sarah Jones of Newport Joseph Lee, Esq. of Red Brooke, Chester Rectory of Aldermaston (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Mortgage, 18 December 1826 Joseph Harris of Ramsgate William Robinson of Ramsgate Wellington Crescent Kent (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Indenture of assignment, 29 September 1865 James Levy Hart of Pembridge Square, Baywater James Jeffries of Poole Street, Middlesex Parcel of land on Poole Street (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Charge to secure loan, 16 October 1905 William H. Humphries, Bart. London Life Association Ltd. (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Conveyance, 21 April 1920 Charles, Earl of Gainsborough, et al. Trustees of Henry, Earl of Lonsdale Land at Langham, Rutland (Box 11, Folder 10)